A Guide to the Credit Women International Collection, 1984-1989
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Special Collections, James Madison University
Credit Women International Collection, 1984-1989
Special Collections, James Madison University
SC 5060
1 Hollinger box (.417 linear feet)
Materials present in this collection consist of two scrap books donated to Special Collections. This includes newsletters, photographs, flyers, and articles about the organization. It fills one Hollinger box and consists of 34 folders.
Credit Women International, Harrisonburg, Virginia Chapter
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
Two scrapbooks were donated by Anne Harter on 7/14/2010
Biographical Information
The Credit Women International is an organization in which women who are involved in a credit union can join. The Harrisonburg chapter was influential in establishing many other chapters, including the Winchester, Virginia chapter in 1985. The organization also held many fundraisers and met once a month with leading professionals in the area often addressing the organization.
Scope and Content
Materials present in this collection consist of two scrapbooks donated to Special Collections. This includes newsletters, photographs, flyers and articles about the organization. It fills one Hollinger box and consists of 34 folders.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in II series:
I: Scrapbook, 1984-1985
II: Scrapbook 1985-1986
Contents List
- Scrapbook, 1984-1985
  - November 1984 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Executive Committee of Harrisonburg CWI
    - Lazarus, fine fashions of Virginia
    - Ron Powell
    - Steve Hall
    - CWI Emergency Medical Record I.D. Card
    - November 1984 Newsletter
  - December 1984 (Box-folder 1:1)
    - Regular Meeting CWI Harrisonburg Part 1
    - Regular Meeting Harrisonburg CWI Part 2
    - Newsletter #11
    - Comic
  - January 1985 (Box:folder 1:3)
    - Stickers
    - Picture of a Man Speaking
    - CWI is Love
    - Regular Meeting- Harrisonburg CWI
    - Credit Women News Clipping
    - Notes from David's Speaking on 3c's of Success (Part 1)
    - Notes from David's Speaking on 3c's of success (Part 2)
    - City Chamber Plans Dale Carnegie Class
    - "What the Dale Carnegie Course Can Help You Do For Yourself" pamphlet
    - January 1985 Newsletter
  - February 1985 (Box:folder 1:4)
    - 1984-1985 Dist. XII Conference- Pittsburgh PA Tour Speakers and Banquets
    - 1984-1985 Dist. XII Conference- Pittsburgh PA Tour Speakers and Banquets
    - 1984-1985 Dist. XII Conference- Pittsburgh PA Tour Speakers and Banquets
    - 1984-1985 Dist. XII Conference- Pittsburgh PA Tour Speakers and Banquets
    - 1984-1985 Dist. XII Conference- Pittsburgh PA Tour Speakers and Banquets
    - 1984-1985 Dist. XII Conference- Pittsburgh PA Tour Speakers and Banquets
    - 1984-1985 Dist. XII Conference- Pittsburgh PA Tour Speakers and Banquets
    - 1984-1985 Dist. XII Conference- Pittsburgh PA Tour Speakers and Banquets
    - District XII 1984-1985 1st Flight- Pittsburgh, PA Accident for Attention
    - 1984-1985 Dist. XII Conference- Pittsburgh Int. Pres. Anne and Int. V. Pres
    - 1984-1985 District XII- Pittsburgh Banquets and Meetings
    - Two Women in a Bed
    - Women with Wine Bottle
    - Instillation Banquet, February 17, 1985
    - Greater Pittsburgh International Airport Pamphlet
    - Newsletter #10
    - This Week In Pittsburgh Key
    - 42nd Annual Mid-Atlantic Consumer Credit and Collection Conference (Itinerary)
    - Conference News
    - Greater Pittsburgh International Airport Stand Pamphlet
    - Pittsburgh Marriott Map
    - 42nd Annual Mid-Atlantic Consumer Credit and Collection Conference (Mixer)
    - 42nd Annual Mid-Atlantic Consumer Credit and Collection Conference (Instillation and Awards Banquet)
    - 42nd Annual Mid-Atlantic Consumer Credit and Collection Conference (Coffee and Danish)
    - 42nd Annual Mid-Atlantic Consumer Credit and Collection Conference (Instillation Banquet)
    - Annual Instillation Banquet
    - Point to Your Future in Credit
    - Elizabeth Allebaugh February Meeting on Consumer Credit Education
    - District Twelve Conference
    - February 1985 Newsletter
  - March 1985 (Box:folder 1:5)
    - Hi Ann! (March 16, 1985)
    - Bridal Shower at Regular Meeting for Stephanie Carr
    - Pictures at March 1985 Meeting
    - Pictures at 1985 Meeting
    - Pictures at 1985 Meeting
    - Community Mediation Center Pamphlet
    - Instillation Ceremony, September Meeting, 1985 Membership Drive, 1984-1985
    - March Meeting and Instillation, Stephanie Carr and Mary Phillips
    - Grand Piano and Furniture Co. History of Shirley Ann Southerly
    - Vicky S. Wenger History
    - Alice Coffman Martens History
    - Teresa A. Breeden History
    - Community Mediation Center
    - Community Mediation Center
    - Mary Lynn Rexrode History
    - Williette S. Moyers History
    - The Women Executive Pamphlet
    - Comic
    - Instillation Ceremony, March 19, 1985
    - Community Mediation Center Letter
    - March 1985 Newsletter
  - April 1985 (Box:folder 1:6)
    - Harrisonburg Daily News Record Credit Women, April 1985
    - Valley Charter
    - National Consumer Credit Week 1985
    - Easter Wishes for You
    - Credit Women News Clipping (Lyle Cameron)
    - Public Record Bulletin
    - April 1985 Newsletter
  - May 1985 (Box:folder 1:7)
    - 'Grace Heatwole-Color Consultant'
    - Credit Women International Of Virginia, Anne L. Harter
    - Credit Women News Clipping John Sowers
    - 'Man At Lecture'
    - 'At a Meeting around a Table'
    - 'Man Presenting to a Group'
    - Executive Board
    - Women Talking Around A Table
    - Women at a Park Bench
    - Front Table
    - Man Speaking at Front Table
    - Woman addressing at Front Table
    - VA Conference May, 1985-Omni- Norfolk Business Meeting Election of Officers
    - CWI- May Meeting- Guests
    - Letter to Debbie from Anne Harter
    - Discover the Many sides of Waterside
    - Virginia Retail Merchants Association
    - Omni Conference Itinerary
    - Omni Button Cover
    - Portside Pamphlet
    - Virginia Credit Women International Program
    - Omni International Hotel Pamphlet
    - Omni Hotel Receipt
    - May 1985 Newsletter
    - Awards and Instillation Luncheon, May 19, 1985
    - Flowers
    - Women in Pink Dresses
    - Virginia State Conference May, 1985-Omni- Norfolk Speakers, Banquet and Tours
    - Virginia State Conference May, 1985-Omni- Norfolk Speakers, Banquet and Tours
    - Virginia State Conference May, 1985-Omni- Norfolk Speakers, Banquet and Tours
    - Ways and Means- May 1985, Bake Sale at Valley Mall
    - Harrisonburg-Rockingham Chamber of Commerce Report
  - June 1985 (Box:folder 1:8)
    - News Letter June 1985
    - Prospective Member Letter June 1985
    - May Meeting 1985 Speaker Violet Allain Professor JMU "Management- Two Perspectives"
    - A Letter from Mary Miller
    - Thank You Letter from Margaret Pitcher
    - Letter from Bonnie Dispanet
    - International Credit Conference Toronto, June 16-18, 1985
    - Roanoke Executive Wins Award of Excellence
    - International Credit Conference Optional Tours
    - The Inner Circle
    - Bonie C. Dispanet Stepping Down Letter
  - July 1985 (Box:folder 1:9)
    - July Newsletter 1985
    - William Page Presenting at the Meeting
    - William Page Card
    - July Meeting-1985-Speaker- William Page Val Com Computer Center "Computers for Small Bus."
  - August 1985 (Box:folder 1:11)
    - August 1985 Newsletter
    - Education Award Certificate Credit Women (100% Passed Exam)
    - Letter from Esther Washington
    - Criteria for Candidate Nomination, CWI Boss of the Year
    - XWI Officers in Training Seminar
    - Leadership Seminary, Dist. XII-Charlottesville, Aug. 24, 1984
    - Leadership Seminary, Dist. XII-Charlottesville, Aug. 24, 1984
    - Itinerary August 24, 1985
    - CWI Boss of the Year Application
    - Valley Chatter
  - September 1985 (Box:folder 1:11)
    - September Newsletter
    - September Meeting- 1985, Speaker Jerry Hopkins (1984 Boss of the Year) "The Sweet Juicy Gapes Can Be Yours" (Plus other Topic)
    - "The Sweet Juicy Grapes Can Be Yours" Address
    - September Meeting- 1985 Installation New Members (membership drive
    - Women Inducted
    - Acceptance letter from Leonard R. Shifflette
    - Fashion Show Pictures
    - Fashion Show Pictures
    - Fashion Show Pictures
    - Fashion Show Pictures
    - Fashion Show Pictures
    - Fashion Show Pictures
    - Fashion Show Pictures
    - Fashion Show Pictures
    - Fashion Show Pictures
    - Stress and Fashion Seminary Planned
    - Invitation to Roanoke's Installation
    - A Seminar for Today's Women
    - A Seminar for Today's Women
    - List of What Women Were Wearing and Price
  - Installation of Winchester's CWI (Box:folder 1:12)
    - Installation of New Officers, November 12, 1985
    - News Clipping, 2nd Meeting- Winchester Election of Officers and By Lws Dist. and State Officer in Attendance Eva Lineberry and Nancy Gibson
    - Newly Elected Officers- CWI Winchester, VA
    - Newspaper Clipping, Credit Women International
    - New Club Formed
    - New Club Formed
    - New Club Formed
    - Agenda
    - Welcome CWI Letter to Deborah from Esther
    - Credit Women International Meeting- Winchester, VA
    - Presentation of Charter of CWI of the Shenandoah Valley
    - State Officer Nancy Gibson VA State 1st VP, District Officer, Eva Lineberry 1st VP
    - International Officer Veni Whill, International Secretary, CWI of the Shenandoah Valley Officers, 1985-1986
    - Installation of New officers CWI of the Shen. Valley, Winchester, VA. Presentation of Gavel to Winchester CWI from Harrisonburg CWI
    - Speaker- Finance One, Winchester VA
    - 4th Meeting- Winchester VA, Presentation of Charter, Anna Claytor, H’burg pres. Anne Harter, H’Burg Past Pres, Debbie Wakeman, Winchester Pres, Meeting Presentation of Chapter District XII President
    - Letter from Debbie C. Wakeman
  - October 1985 (Box:folder 1:13)
    - Invitation
    - Invitation
    - Invitation
    - Invitation
    - Club Auction
    - Club Auction
    - Way and Means Project
    - Hampton CWI Denial
    - Hagerstown Maryland Invitation
    - Petersburg CWI Bosses Banquet Invitation
    - Decline from Marilyn Landers
    - Charlottesville Invitation
    - Promissory Note
    - CWI Sixth Annual; Bosses Night and Installation
    - CWI Sixth Annual; Bosses Night and Installation
    - CWI Sixth Annual; Bosses Night and Installation
    - CWI Sixth Annual; Bosses Night and Installation
    - Skit for Bosses Night
    - CWI Sixth Annual; Bosses Night and Installation
    - CWI Sixth Annual; Bosses Night and Installation
    - Valley Charter
    - CWI Sixth Annual; Bosses Night and Installation
    - CWI Sixth Annual; Bosses Night and Installation
    - CWI Sixth Annual; Bosses Night and Installation
    - Presentation of Marth B. Gleason Bracelet from Immediate Past President given by Martha to H’burg Club- Installation of New Officers 1985-1986
    - Letter From Pat Batten
    - Presentation of 5 Year Perfect Attendance Award- Anne Anve
    - Letter from Anna
    - Thanks From Anne
    - Thanks From Anne Vance
    - Ron and Anne
    - Pilot Club Installs Vance as President
    - Bowen is Promoted
    - Kline Attends Credit School
    - Dispanet Named to CAM Board
    - Harrisonburg Pilot
    - First American Names Manager
    - Dinne Dean and Mary Rexrode
    - Phyllis Kline and Karen Thompson
    - Angie Arndt and Betty Propst (Credit Bureau Staff)
    - Karen Thompson and Sara Bailey (Credit Bureau Staff)
    - Anne Vance
    - Anna Claytor
    - Linda Ritche
    - Take it From One Who Knows, Don't Give All to Family, Job
    - Penney Official Speaks on Credit
    - Sears Considering General Purpose Credit Card
    - Consumers Advised to Check Credit Files
    - Dun and Bradstreet Sells Data on Contractors
    - Employees' Appearance Reflects on Company’s Business Image
    - News Letter, October 1985
  - Pamphlets and Articles (Box:folder 1:14)
    - How the New Equal Credit Opportunity Act Affects You
    - How To Establish and Use Credit
    - Your Credit Rating
    - What the Credit Granter Needs to Know About th Fair Credit Reporting Act
    - Consumers, Credit Bureaus and the Fair Credit Reporting Act
    - Credit Reporting Industry Security Standards
    - Credit Creditability
    - Solving Credit Problems
    - $50,000 to $100,000 Group Term Life Insurance
    - How the New Equal Opportunity Act Affects You
    - Credit and Collection Clinic
    - Consumer Trials
    - Consumers, Collectors and the Fair Credit Collection Practices Act
    - What the Credit Grantor Needs To Know About the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act
    - Your Credit Rating
    - Electronic Fund Transfer (Regulation E)
    - Options for Savers
    - Highlights of the Fair Credit Reporting Act For Credit Grantors
    - Bankruptcy Strategies for Creditors
    - Notice to Consumers
    - Virginia General District Courts Information Pamphlet
    - Virginia Courts in Brief
    - Consumer Credit Protection Act, Amendments
    - Comprehensive Crime Control Act of 1984
    - Title VI- Consumer Credit Reporting
    - Credit Women International -District XII- April 1985
    - Credit Women International- Fall 1984
    - Credit Women International- Spring 1985
    - Management Magazine Conference/Financial Report 1984
    - Credit World 1985 (Vol. 73, No. 3, January/February)
    - Specialist Must Work Alone
    - Young, Old Women Out of Work Find the Job Market is Still Tight
    - Too Old to Get Credit
    - Be Your Own Best Friend
    - Money Talks by Richard Blodgett
    - Credit Cards, Their Use, Abuse Increasing
    - Employers Key on Expression
- Scrapbook, 1988-1989
  - Martinsville Henry County (Box-folder 1:15)
    - Women Posing (Names on Back)
    - Pictures at Bosses Night In Martinsville
    - Bosses Night Invitation to Martinsville
    - Credit Women International of Martinsville and Henry County, Virginia
  - Danville (Box:folder 1:16)
    - To Anne, from Gabriella Lea
    - Coffee Cream, Danville Credit Women
    - Chewing Gum Keeps You Awake Better Than Coffee
    - Danville Installation of Officers
    - Light your Way, Danville Credit Professionals
  - Miscellaneous (Box:folder 1:17)
    - Souvenir Impression of the Seal of the Treasurer of the Sovereign State of West Virginia
    - Annual Installation Banquet
    - A. James Manchin, Treasurer of State
    - CWI: Credit Professionals, Mid-Atlantic Council Newsletter #3
    - Luncheon, CWI, District XII, Arlington
    - Anne, from Mary Rexrode
    - Annual Installation Banquet, March 20, 1989
    - 77th Annual International Credit Conference
    - 77th Annual International Credit Conference
    - 77th Annual International Credit Conference
    - Anne's Name Tag
    - Not from Nancy Gibson
    - Name Tag, Anne Harter
    - Thanks from Hazel
    - Congratulations from Jay
    - Morning Worship, April 24, 1988
    - Belegate Ribbon
    - To Anne, From Dot
    - Image Impact Workshop
    - Virginia State President Workshop
    - Congratulations from Divine Jeannie, and Mary
    - Congratulations from Dot
    - Virginia CWI Credit Professionals Breakfast
    - Congratulations from Jo
    - Forty-Eight Installation Banquet Mid-Atlantic Council District Twelve, March 20, 1988
    - Anne, From Eva
    - To Anne, From Sheryl
    - Congratulations From Phyllis Caffrey
    - Virginia CWI: Credit Professionals 26th Installation and Awards Banquet
    - 27th Annual State Conference
    - Anne From Venie B. Whitt
    - CWI Credit Professionals of Pennsylvania State Conference, September 1988
    - Note From Benie Whitt, re: Anne Harter's Travels
    - Letter to Anne from JoAnne
    - Newsletter #3, March 27, 1989
    - Itinerary for Virginia State Conference, April 21-23, 1989
    - Spring State Conference Newsletter
    - Newsletter #2, November
    - Flyer #3, April 7, 1989
    - Newsletter #1, April 1988
    - Newsletter #8, November 1988
    - Newsletter #11, February 1989
    - Newsletter #12, March 1989
    - To Anne, From Phyllis
    - Newsletter #1 August 1998
    - Newsletters 2,3,4,5,6,7 October 1988-April 1989
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Women Around a table
  - Staunton, Winchester, Augusta County (Box:folder 1:18)
    - Members at a Barbeque
    - Credit Professionals Officers Installed
    - CWI Professionals, Staunton, Waynesboro, and Augusta County
    - Key
    - First Annual Bosses Night, October 11, 1988
  - Charlottesville (Box:folder 1:19)
    - Photos of Members (Description in Folder)
    - Photos of Members (Description in Folder)
    - Invitation
    - Bosses Banquet 1989
    - Speech for Installation
  - Covington Clifton Forge (Box:folder 1:20)
    - Bosses Night, April 15, 1989
    - Officers Installed
    - Photos of Members
    - Nancy from Janis
    - Covington-Clifton Forge Credit Women Professionals
    - Invitation
  - Hampton (Box:folder 1:21)
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Invitation to Bosses Banquet
    - Hampton Bosses Banquet, September 22, 1988
  - Lexington Buena Vista (Box:folder 1:22)
    - Anne from Doris and all Members
    - Memo From Anne Harter
  - Lynchburg (Box:folder 1:23)
    - Officers for 87-88, Lynchburg CWI
    - CWI, 41st Annual Bosses' Banquet October 6th, 1988
    - Invitation Lynchburg's Bosses Night
  - Petersburg (Box:folder 1:24)
    - Blank meeting List Notes
    - Newsletter #3, January 24, 1989
    - Invitation to Petersburg Installation and Bosses Banquet
    - Members (Two Women)
    - Members (Two Women)
  - Credit Women International 1984-1985 Harrisonburg, VA (Box:folder 1:25)
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Newsletter #3 Oct. and Nov. 1984
    - To Anne From Esther Worthington
    - Newsletter # 1 October 1984
    - Congratulations from Kristie
    - Skit
    - Anne Harter Name Tag
    - Shield Pin
    - CWI Installs New Officers
    - President Installed
    - Credit Women International of Harrisonburg, VA 1984-1985 Committees
    - Valley Chatter
    - Roster
    - Presidents Message
    - CWI October 16, 1984
  - Suffolk (Box:folder 1:26)
    - Harter Named State CWI President
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Thank You From Hazel
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Harrisonburg CWI
    - With Congratulations from Juniata
    - VP Spreads Word on CWI
    - Speech
    - Speech for Installation of Officers
    - Update from Gail C. Williams
    - Fruit Basket Drink and Peanuts from Gail and Lucy
    - Bosses Banquet Invitation
    - Thank You from Gail
    - Anne Harter Name Tag
    - Suffolk CWI: Credit Professionals Bosses' Banquet
  - Northern Virginia Fairfax (Box:folder 1:27)
    - Last Minute Memo
    - 49th Installation Banquet Mid-Atlantic Council District 12
    - Anne Harter Name Tag
    - Installation Banquet Invitation and Photos
    - Thanks from Frances
    - You've Come A Long Way Baby
  - Newport News
    - Saint Vincent de Paul Church, November 29, 1988
    - Inside Business
    - Photos of Members
    - Invitation to CWI Bosses Banquet
    - Bosses Banquet and Installation of Officers, October 5, 1988
    - Membership Bulletin, January 1989
    - First Impression
    - Join a Winning Team of Credit Professionals
    - First Impressions, March 4, 1989
  - Harrisonburg (Box:folder 1:29)
    - Bankruptcy Increase Costly for Consumers
    - Club Notes
    - Thank You Anne From Alice Martens
    - Business People and Dorothy R. Hinnant
    - Carrier of the Year
    - Certificate of Perfect Attendance to Anne Harter
    - Harrisonburg CWI: CP Installation, October 18, 1988
    - CWI-Credit Professionals, Bosses Banquet/Installation, October 18,1988
  - Norfolk (Box:folder 1:30)
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Speech
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - Photos of Members (Descriptions on Paper/Back)
    - CWI-CP Officers Norfolk, VA 1989-1989
    - Bosses Night, October 4, 1988
  - Shenandoah Valley (Box:folder 1:31)
    - CWI Previews, March 1989
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - CWI Bosses Night, March 21, 1989
    - Thank You Anne From Cindy McClain
    - Invitation to Installation Meeting, October 11, 1988
    - Thank You Anne From Cindy McClain
    - CWI Credit Professionals, Bosses Night Invitation, March 21, 1989
    - CWI Credit Professionals of the Shenandoah Valley, Installation of Officers
    - CWI Credit Professionals of the Shenandoah Valley, Bosses Night, March,8 1988
    - Anne harter Name Tag
  - Roanoke (Box:folder 1:32)
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Reach for the Stars
    - Thank You Anne From Grace
    - Installation of Officers, September 15, 1988
    - Name Tag
    - Club News
    - CWI: Credit Professionals of Roanoke, 1988-1989
    - Invitations to President's Tea
    - CWI Credit Professionals Elect Officers
    - Credit Professionals Elect New Officers
    - Grace Pff Will Speak for CWI
    - President's Tea Napkin
    - The Jefferson Club Napkin
    - Photos of Members
    - Bosses Night, May 10, 1988
  - Richmond (Box:folder 1:33)
    - Photos of Members
    - Photos of Members
    - Education Communication "Progress Through Communication Strength Through Education"
  - Portsmouth (Box:folder 1:34)
    - Invitation to Bosses Banquet
    - Late Summer Luau, September 20, 1988
    - Photos of Members
    - Tick to Bosses Banquet
    - Name Tag
    - Photos of Members